export const questions =[
    {
        "question": "For what values of K does the equation x^2 + (k - 2)x + k + 1 = 0 have equal roots?",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What value of 'a' will the equation x^2 + (3a + 1)x + a^2 - 1 = 5a have equal roots?",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the values of p, q, and r if 3x^2 - 12x + 6 = P(x + q)^2 + r.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prove that the equation k^2 - 2pk + 3p^2 + q = 0 where p and q are constants cannot have real roots if p and q are real.",
        "options": ["True", "False", "Cannot be determined", "Depends on p", "Depends on q"],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "For what values of 'a' will the equation ax^2 - 6x + 3a = 0 have coincident roots?",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation p^2 - 3p + 2 = 0, find α + β.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation p^2 - 3p + 2 = 0, find α^2 + β^2.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation p^2 - 3p + 2 = 0, find α - β.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation p^2 - 3p + 2 = 0, find α^2 - β^2.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation (x - 3/4)^2 - 17/16 = 0, find α^2/β^2.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation (x - 3/4)^2 - 17/16 = 0, find β^2/α^2.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation (x - 3/4)^2 - 17/16 = 0, find α + β.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation 5x^2 - x = 10 form the equation whose roots are α + 1 and β + 1.",
        "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation t^2 + qt - 10 = 0 and α^2 + β^2 = 29, show that the value of q is ±3.",
        "options": ["True", "False", "Cannot be determined", "Depends on α", "Depends on β"],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given that one of the roots of the equation px^2 + qx + r = 0 is two times the other, prove that the roots are -q/3a and -2q/3a.",
        "options": ["True", "False", "Depends on p", "Depends on q", "Depends on r"],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Using the definition of inverse, find the inverse of a matrix A given that AB=BA=I and A is a square matrix of order 3.",
        "options": [
            "A. Inverse does not exist",
            "B. A^-1 = B",
            "C. A^-1 = A",
            "D. A^-1 = I",
            "E. Not enough information to determine"
        ],
        "answer": "B. A^-1 = B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Suppose K = [3 2; 1 -4], L = [a b; c d], and KL=LK=I. Find the values of a, b, c, and d.",
        "options": [
            "A. a=3, b=2, c=1, d=-4",
            "B. a=4/13, b=-2/13, c=-1/13, d=3/13",
            "C. a=1/4, b=1/2, c=1, d=-4",
            "D. a=3/13, b=2/13, c=1/13, d=-4/13",
            "E. No solution"
        ],
        "answer": "D. a=3/13, b=2/13, c=1/13, d=-4/13"
    },
    {
        "question": "For what values of p and q is the matrix A = [[p-q, p+q]; [p+q, p-q]] an identity?",
        "options": [
            "A. p=0, q=0",
            "B. p=1, q=0",
            "C. p=0, q=1",
            "D. p=1, q=1",
            "E. No values of p and q make A an identity"
        ],
        "answer": "E. No values of p and q make A an identity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Solve the following system of linear equations using Cramer's rule: 2x + y - 3z = 5, 3x - 2y + 2z = 5, 5x - 3y - z = 16",
        "options": [
            "A. x=2, y=1, z=-1",
            "B. x=1, y=2, z=3",
            "C. x=2, y=-1, z=1",
            "D. x=3, y=2, z=1",
            "E. No solution"
        ],
        "answer": "A. x=2, y=1, z=-1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Using Gaussian elimination method, solve the equations 5p + 7q - r = -29, -13p + 17q + 19r = 37, p - 2q + 3r = 15",
        "options": [
            "A. p=1, q=2, r=3",
            "B. p=2, q=-1, r=1",
            "C. p=3, q=2, r=1",
            "D. p=2, q=1, r=-1",
            "E. No solution"
        ],
        "answer": "B. p=2, q=-1, r=1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Solve the linear system using the inverse matrix method: 6x₁ - 4x₂ + 3x₃ = -4, 14x₁ + 2x₂ - 6x₃ = 9, -4x₁ + x₂ + 9x₃ = 3",
        "options": [
            "A. x₁=1, x₂=2, x₃=3",
            "B. x₁=2, x₂=-1, x₃=1",
            "C. x₁=3, x₂=2, x₃=1",
            "D. x₁=2, x₂=1, x₃=-1",
            "E. No solution"
        ],
        "answer": "C. x₁=3, x₂=2, x₃=1"
    },
    {
        "question": "A couple has ₦10,000 to invest. As their financial consultant, you recommend they invest in Treasury bills that yield 6%, Treasury bonds that yield 8%, and Corporate bonds that yield 10%. The couple wants to have an annual income of ₦680 and the amount invested in Corporate bonds must be half that invested in Treasury bills. Find the amount in each investment.",
        "options": [
            "A. Treasury bills: ₦4,000, Treasury bonds: ₦3,000, Corporate bonds: ₦2,000",
            "B. Treasury bills: ₦3,000, Treasury bonds: ₦4,000, Corporate bonds: ₦2,000",
            "C. Treasury bills: ₦2,000, Treasury bonds: ₦3,000, Corporate bonds: ₦4,000",
            "D. Treasury bills: ₦2,000, Treasury bonds: ₦4,000, Corporate bonds: ₦3,000",
            "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Treasury bills: ₦4,000, Treasury bonds: ₦3,000, Corporate bonds: ₦2,000"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the function y = ax² + bx + c passing through the points (1, -1), (3, -1), and (-2, 14). Use the system of linear equations approach.",
        "options": [
            "A. y = 2x² - 3x + 2",
            "B. y = -2x² + 3x - 2",
            "C. y = 3x² - 2x + 1",
            "D. y = -3x² + 2x - 1",
            "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. y = -2x² + 3x - 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "The system below is derived from an electrical circuit by the application of Kirchhoff's voltage rule: 2i₂ = 4, 8 = 5i₄ + i₁, Find i₁, i₂, i₃, and i₄.",
        "options": [
            "A. i₁ = 2, i₂ = 2, i₃ = 4, i₄ = 1",
            "B. i₁ = 2, i₂ = 2, i₃ = 1, i₄ = 4",
            "C. i₁ = 4, i₂ = 2, i₃ = 1, i₄ = 2",
            "D. i₁ = 1, i₂ = 2, i₃ = 4, i₄ = 2",
            "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. i₁ = 2, i₂ = 2, i₃ = 4, i₄ = 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Determine the number of insects at t = 0 for the function P(t) = 500e^(0.02t).",
        "options": ["0 insects", "500 insects", "1000 insects", "200 insects", "800 insects"],
        "answer": "500 insects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the rate of decay of strontium 90 according to A(t) = A₀e^(-0.0244t)?",
        "options": ["0.01", "0.02", "0.0244", "0.05", "0.10"],
        "answer": "0.0244"
    },
  
    {
        "question": "Given a population of rabbits with an exponential growth rate of 11.7% per day and initial population of 100, what will the population be after 7 days?",
        "options": ["200 rabbits", "220 rabbits", "235 rabbits", "250 rabbits", "270 rabbits"],
        "answer": "235 rabbits"
    },
    
    {
        "question": "For a lake with 400 fish and a limiting population of 2500, what is the population after t = 0 months?",
        "options": ["2500 fish", "1000 fish", "400 fish", "600 fish", "500 fish"],
        "answer": "400 fish"
    },
    {
        "question": "√28 may be written as _____.",
        "options": [
          "A. 2√7",
          "B. 7√2",
          "C. 2√2",
          "D. 4√7",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. 2√7"
      },
      {
        "question": "Rationalizing the denominator of 1/√5 gives _____.",
        "options": [
          "A. 5/√5",
          "B. 1",
          "C. √5/√5",
          "D. √5/5",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. √5/5"
      },
      {
        "question": "The 7th term of an AP is -39/12 and the 15th term is -103/12. What is the 27th term?",
        "options": [
          "A. -187/12",
          "B. -191/12",
          "C. -199/12",
          "D. -205/12",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. -199/12"
      },
      {
        "question": "In an AP of 21 terms, the sum of the first 3 terms is – 33 and that of the middle 3 is 75. What is the sum of the AP?",
        "options": [
          "A. -955",
          "B. -1155",
          "C. 525",
          "D. 715",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 525"
      },
      {
        "question": "The 6th term of an AP is 6 and the 16th term is 14. What is the 27th term?",
        "options": [
          "A. 106/5",
          "B. 22/5",
          "C. 118/5",
          "D. 114/5",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 114/5"
      },
      {
        "question": "In an AP, the ratio of the 2nd term to the 7th term is 1/3. If the 5th term is 11, what is the 15th term?",
        "options": [
          "A. 28",
          "B. 31",
          "C. 33",
          "D. 36",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 33"
      },
      {
        "question": "The sum of the first 3 terms in an AP is 6 and that of the last 3 is 16. If the AP has 13 terms, what is the sum of the middle three terms?",
        "options": [
          "A. 7",
          "B. 9",
          "C. 11",
          "D. 13",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 11"
      },
      {
        "question": "In an AP, the ratio of the 7th term to the 10th term is -1. If the 16th term is -15, what is the 3rd term?",
        "options": [
          "A. 11",
          "B. 13",
          "C. -11",
          "D. -13",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. -11"
      },
      {
        "question": "In an AP, the sum of the first 3 terms is -36 and that of the last 3 is 27. If there are 10 terms, what are the 1st term and the common difference respectively?",
        "options": [
          "A. 15, 3",
          "B. -15, 3",
          "C. 15, -3",
          "D. -15, -3",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. -15, -3"
      },
      {
        "question": "In an AP, the sum of the first 3 terms is – 60 and that of the last 3 is 84. If there are 15 terms, what is the sum of the middle 3 terms?",
        "options": [
          "A. 8",
          "B. 12",
          "C. 16",
          "D. 24",
          "E. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 16"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which trigonometric function can equal or be greater than 1.000?",
        "options": [
          "Sine",
          "Cosine",
          "Tangent",
          "None of the above",
          "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Tangent"
      },
      {
        "question": "A plane ascends at a 40° angle. When it reaches an altitude of one hundred feet, how much ground distance has it covered? To solve, use the trigonometric chart. Round the answer to the nearest tenth.",
        "options": [
          "64.3 feet",
          "76.6 feet",
          "80.1 feet",
          "119.2 feet",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "119.2 feet"
      },
      {
        "question": "A 20 ft. beam leans against a wall. The beam reaches the wall 13.9 ft. above the ground. What is the measure of the angle formed by the beam and the ground?",
        "options": [
          "44°",
          "35°",
          "55°",
          "46°",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "44°"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which set of angles has the same trigonometric ratio?",
        "options": [
          "Sin 45 and tan 45",
          "Sin 30 and cos 60",
          "Cos 30 and tan 45",
          "Tan 60 and sin 45",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Sin 30 and cos 60"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the sum of trigonometric ratios Sin 54 and Cos 36?",
        "options": [
          "0.809",
          "1.618",
          "1.000",
          "1.536",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1.618"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the sum of trigonometric ratios Sin 33 and Sin 57?",
        "options": [
          "0.545",
          "1.000",
          "1.090",
          "1.383",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1.090"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the sum of trigonometric ratios Cos 16 and Cos 74?",
        "options": [
          "0.276",
          "0.961",
          "1.237",
          "1.922",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1.237"
      },
      {
        "question": "In △ABC, vertex C is a right angle. Which trigonometric ratio has the same trigonometric value as Sin A?",
        "options": [
          "Sin B",
          "Cosine A",
          "Cosine B",
          "Tan A",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Cosine B"
      },
      {
        "question": "In △ABC, Tan ∠A = 3/4. The hypotenuse of △ABC is:",
        "options": [
          "3",
          "4",
          "5",
          "9",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "5"
      },
      {
        "question": "In △ABC, Sin ∠B = 14/17. The hypotenuse of △ABC is:",
        "options": [
          "14",
          "17",
          "√485",
          "0.824",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "17"
      },
      {
        "question": "In △ABC, Cos ∠C = 22/36. The hypotenuse is:",
        "options": [
          "22",
          "36",
          "0.611",
          "2√445",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "36"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the correct definition of Sine (Sin)?",
        "options": [
          "Adjacent / Hypotenuse",
          "Hypotenuse / Adjacent",
          "Hypotenuse / Opposite",
          "Opposite / Hypotenuse",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Opposite / Hypotenuse"
      }
]




